Abdul Saboor Sohaib

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Email | Github | Linkedin Twitter | Portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Aseel (Kabul, Afghanistan) **On-site Front-end Developer** (Full Time) Nov 2023 – Aug 2024

- Worked on multiple products that improved user engagement and streamlined customer interactions, resulting in a 10% increase in sales.
- Led efforts to optimize product performance by identifying and resolving key technical issues, and improving page load times and user satisfaction.
- Worked closely with marketing, product, and do-good teams to ensure seamless product launches, improving communication and reducing project turnaround time by 15%.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS,

Remote

Full Stack Developer (Full Time) Aug 2022 – Nov 2023 Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Authentication, Authorization, and Testing) while building multiple full-stack and front-end projects independently and via pair programming (as a team).

- Built the entire front end of the application with React and Redux.
- Identified areas for modification and improvements within a short period.
- Successfully modified numerous software applications that increased user-friendliness by 20%.

JUUBIX (London, United Kingdom) Remote
Front-end Developer (Part-Time) July 2023 – Aug 2023

- Lead and motivate the team to achieve their goals.
- Contribute to different projects with different technology.

MICROVERSE (San Francisco, California, USA) Remote
Mentor (Volunteer) (Part-Time) Sep 2022 – Nov 2022

- Mentored 5+ junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews through Zoom and Slack.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by 80%.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program for 5 junior web developers.

Summary:

Full Stack Developer with over 2+ years of experience, Successfully developed and contributed to 30+ projects as a team player. Good leadership. communication, teamwork, and problem-solving skills, with a strong ability to mentor junior developers and collaborate effectively in remote environments. Experienced in improving project efficiency, optimizing user experiences, and delivering high-quality software solutions.

SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3 JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Redux, Redux toolkit, React Query, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Nest.js, Prisma, and PostgreSQL.

Soft Skills: Leadership, Communication, Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Mentoring, Remote Pair-Programming, Quick Learning, Planning, and Collaboration.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Vercel, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Aug 2022 - June 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program (Full-Time)

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Jahan University Bachelor of Computer Science

Aug 2019 - June 2024

- Data structures and algorithms and the Theory of automata.
- Digital Logic and Design with Mathematics.
- Database Management Systems.
- Human-Computer Interaction.
- Web design and development tools.

PROJECTS

World Vision Clinic

- World Vision Clinic is a professional web application that provides users with doctor profiles and a user-friendly appointment booking system, streamlining the process of selecting and scheduling appointments.
- Built with: (Ruby on Rails,

React, and PostgreSQL)

Budget Tracker

- Budget Tracker is a user-friendly web application designed to help users effortlessly add categories and track expenses, providing a streamlined and efficient way to manage their financial transactions.
- Built with: (Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and Bootstrap)

Space Travelers Hub

- Space Travelers Hub is a cutting-edge React application that empowers users to effortlessly book and cancel rocket reservations. Leveraging API integration.
- Built with: (React, Redux, and Bootstrap)